



PAUL M HERMAI

Sanford, FL 32771

(C) 407-414-5903 | pmherman85@icloud.com LinkedIn: http://linkedin.com/in/pmherman85 Github: https://github.com/pmherman Portfolio: http://paulmherman.com

Professional Summary

An organized, detail-oriented, and conscientious self-starter, able to strategize and prioritize effectively to accomplish multiple tasks and stay calm under pressure, while being an experienced supervisor and trainer; able to explain information clearly, recognize excellence in individuals, and inspire team members to achieve their potential while working toward common goals and grow within an organization.

Skills

- Process implementation
- Staff development
- Typing speed 100 WPM
- Regional level facilitation, coaching and training
- Provide constructive feedback
- Receive Feedback
- Interview/Hire & Supervise Employees
- Knowledgable with Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop,
- Premiere, Indesign) Knowledgable with Apple and Microsoft based systems
- Proficient with Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel and Access
- HTML5, CSS3

- JavaScript, JQuery,
- Twitter Bootstrap
- **AJAX**
- Firebase
- PHP
- SQL
- Node.is
- Express.js
- MongoDB • Express-Handlebars
- ReactJS
- Hardware & Software deployment
- A+ Hardware/Software Coursework

Education

Full Stack Coding Boot Camp University of Central Florida

University of Phoenix

Bachelor of Science: Information Technology

Coursework includes speech & communication, information technology with specialization in business and networking.

Certified Pharmacy Technician
Pharmacy Technician Certification Board **Registered Pharmacy Technician**

Florida Department of Health

Sanford, FL 2016

Orlando, FL

2018

2012 (Current and Active)

2010 (Current and Active)

Application's Built

SoundCheck

Project Manager

- HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Ajax, Twitter Bootstrap, Youtube API, Ticketmaster API
- App is designed to load information from bands that will show local concert (if any), videos and images all in one place
- Worked on Front End Code Worked on creation of modal and Firebase integration. Merging code to GitHub
- Development YouTube API integration
- Deployed at: http://pmherman.github.io/soundcheck | Github: https://github.com/pmherman/soundcheck

Liri Node

Backend Developer

- Node.js, Package.json, NPM Packages OMDB, Spotify, Twitter and File System
- Uses CLI and nodeJS to take in use information and output the users last 20 Twitter results, lets them search for movies using the OMDB API and returns the information to the console. Also allows uses to search for song information using the Spotify API.
- Github: https://github.com/pmherman/liri-node-app (NPM install is required to ensure app runs correctly)

Friend Finder

Full Stack Web Developer

- Node.js, Express.js, jQuery, Twitter Bootstrap
- App that uses express to take in a series of questions and based on the average from the questions will calculate your best friend based on the model of options available
 Deployed at: https://morning-plains-43651.herokuapp.com | Github: https://github.com/pmherman/friendfinder

Professional Experience

Store Manager Walgreens Boots Alliance

Mar 2014 - Current

Longwood, FL

- Worked with over 100 Assistant Store Manager Trainees and Shift Leads to achieve new leadership for company.
- Analyzed department documents for appropriate distribution and filing.
- Obtained documents, clearances, certificates and approvals from local, state and federal agencies. Increased store income by \$300,000 YoY
- Analyze business statements to create effective business plans to improve store performance and customer experience. Payroll management, scheduling, cash management, merchandising, time management.

 Managed both hourly and overtime exempt employees, between 25 50 employees at one time.

Assistant Store Manager/Executive Asst. Manager

May 2010 - Mar 2014

Orlando, FL

Walgreens Boots Alliance
Trained and promoted several Shift Leads

- Coached and grew team members
- Improved performance at high volume 24 hour locations.
 Drug Store Management Trainee

Walgreens Boots Alliance

Various other positions within the company since 2003: Service Clerk, Photo/Head Photo Specialist

Apr 2003 - May 2010 Orlando, FL